Guide to the Consumer Reports. Esther Peterson papers, 1953-1997 and undated RL.11791
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Consumer Reports. Esther Peterson papers
1953-1997 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Consumer Reports (Firm)
RL.11791
19.0 Linear Feet
Consumer Reports is a product testing and consumer advocacy nonprofit organization based in Yonkers, N.Y., founded in 1936. Esther Peterson (1906-1997) was a leader in consumer, labor and women's movements who served as the first Special Assistant to the President for Consumer Affairs. The Consumer Reports Esther Peterson papers include correspondence, clippings, photographs, texts of articles and speeches, reports, white papers, and other printed materials. The bulk of the collection documents Peterson's work after leaving government in 1981, especially with the International Organization of Consumer's Unions (IOCU) through the 1980s and early 1990s as well as her involvement with consumer and women's movements. Key correspondents include Peter Hansen, Joan Claybrook, Ralph Nader, and Gus Yatron. Institutions represented include Aetna Insurance, American Council on Consumer Interests (ACCI), Centre for Our Common Future, Consumer Federation of America, Consumer Insurance Interest Group (CIIG), Consumer Product Safety Commission, Consumers Union, IOCU, Professional Insurance Agents (PIA), the United Nations Economic and Social Council (ECOSOC), the United Nations Commission on Transnational Corporations, and the U.S. Office of Consumer Affairs. Topics addressed include: consumer advocacy and protection, environmental regulation, particularly the regulation of pesticides, chemicals, and hazardous substances; insurance and health care, especially women's health and long-term care for the elderly; international development and trade; pharmaceutical exports; and transnational corporations. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
Arrangement
Organized into the following series: General Files; Special Assistant to the President for Consumer Affairs; IOCU/UN; CIIG/PIA; Aetna; Health/Insurance; Printed Materials; Audiovisual Materials
Biographical / Historical
Consumer Reports is a product testing and consumer advocacy nonprofit organization based in Yonkers, N.Y., founded in 1936. Esther Peterson (1906-1997) was a leader in consumer, labor and women's movements who served as the first Special Assistant to the President for Consumer Affairs.
Born in 1906 in Provo, Utah, Esther Peterson was a leader in the labor movement, women's movement, and consumer movement throughout her life.
Early in her career, Mrs. Peterson taught at Branch Agricultural College in Utah, Winsor School in Boston and Bryn Mawr Summer School for Women Workers in Industry. Active in the labor movement since the 1930s, Mrs. Peterson was Assistant Director of Education of the Amalgamated Clothing Workers (1939-1944) and served as the union's representative (1945-1948). From 1957-1961 she was the legislative representative of the Industrial Union department of the AFL-CIO.
She held high-level posts under three United States Presidents. John F. Kennedy appointed her Director of the Women's Bureau in the Labor Department (1961), Assistant Secretary of Labor for Labor Standards (1961-1969), and Executive Vice Chair of the President's Commission on the Status of Women (1961-1963). In 1964, Lyndon B. Johnson appointed her the first Special Assistant to the President for Consumer Affairs, and Chair of the President's Committee on Consumer Interests (1964-1967). She served in this capacity again under President Jimmy Carter.
From 1970-1977, Mrs. Peterson was the Vice President of Consumer Programs and consumer advisor to the President of Giant Food Corporation. In the 1970s and 1980s she appeared on television and on radio talk shows to speak directly to consumers on current issues.
In 1984, Peterson was appointed to be the representative to the Economic and Social Council (ECOSOC) at the United Nations in New York for the International Organization of Consumers Unions (IOCU). In that role, she traveled extensively throughout the United States, Asia, South America, Europe, and Africa. She helped secure the passage of the UN Guidelines for Consumer Protection and the Consolidated List of Products Whose Consumption and/or Sale Have Been Banned, Withdrawn, Severely Restricted or Not Approved by Governments.
Later in life, she became active on issues related to health care and insurance for elder Americans. She was on the Board of Directors of the United Seniors Health Cooperative (USHC), and worked with Aetna on "Choice Time," a consumer education publication on long-term care for elder Americans. In 1987, Mrs. Peterson became Chairperson of the Consumer Insurance Interest Group (CIIG), which worked with the National Association of Professional Insurance Agents (PIA) to develop model standards and a "bill of rights" for insurance consumers during the liability insurance crisis of the late 1980's.
Peterson died in 1997, at the age of 91.
- Source: Biographical notes included in collection and her New York Times obituary, Dec. 22, 1997.
Access Restrictions
Access restricted. Access note. Collection contains fragile audiovisual/photographic formats that may need to be reformatted before use. Contact Research Services for access.
Provenance
The Consumer Reports. Esther Peterson Papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 2019.
Related Materials
Related materials may be found in the following Hartman Center collections:
Eileen Nic Papers
Colston E. Warne Papers
Consumer Reports Washington Office records
Giant food stores advertising collection.
Collection Overview
The Consumer Reports Esther Peterson papers include correspondence, clippings, photographs, texts of articles and speeches, reports, white papers, and other printed materials. The bulk of the collection documents Peterson's work after leaving government in 1981, especially with the International Organization of Consumer's Unions (IOCU) through the 1980s and early 1990s as well as her involvement with consumer and women's movements. Key correspondents include Peter Hansen, Joan Claybrook, Ralph Nader, and Gus Yatron. Institutions represented include Aetna Insurance, American Council on Consumer Interests (ACCI), Centre for Our Common Future, Consumer Federation of America, Consumer Insurance Interest Group (CIIG), Consumer Product Safety Commission, Consumers Union, IOCU, Professional Insurance Agents (PIA), the United Nations Economic and Social Council (ECOSOC), the United Nations Commission on Transnational Corporations, and the U.S. Office of Consumer Affairs. Topics addressed include: consumer advocacy and protection, environmental regulation, particularly the regulation of pesticides, chemicals, and hazardous substances; insurance and health care, especially women's health and long-term care for the elderly; international development and trade; pharmaceutical exports; and transnational corporations.
Consumer advocacy; consumer protection; International organizations; Economic development -- Environmental aspects; Corporate governance; Corporations -- United States -- History; Insurance; Health care -- United States; Women's history -- United States; Economic development; Women in development -- International cooperation; Peterson, Esther, 1906-1997; John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History; International Organization of Consumers' Unions; United Nations
- General Files, 1953-1997 and undated; 1
  Scope and Contents
  The General Files series reflects the range of Peterson's involvement with civic organizations, and the extent to which she had become a leader in the consumer and women's movement later in life. The General series is organized generally by subject.
  - Alphabetical Subject File, 1953-1997 and undated; 1
    - Alice Louise Reynolds Lecture, Brigham Young University, 1988 (Box 1)
    - Australia, 1988; 4 folders (Box 1)
      Third folder includes a speech by Joan Claybrook and Peterson's notes.
    - Beef grading, 1980 (Box 1)
    - Berkshire, 1987 June 19-21 (Box 1)
    - Business, undated (Box 1)
    - China, 1986 (Box 1)
    - Chronological file, 1988 (Box 1)
    - Clean air, 1982 (Box 1)
    - Clippings, 1962 (Box 1)
      Clippings from Esther's time at the Department of Labor and Women's Bureau
    - Clippings and notes, 1982-1984 (Box 19)
      Assorted clippings on the international consumer movement and features on Esther Peterson. A few clippings in Japanese.
    - Clippings--Pharmaceuticals, 1986-1987 (Box 1)
    - Clocks, 1994-1997; 2 folders (Box 1)
    - Concern for Consumers--Notes, undated (Box 1)
      Undated meeting notes on White House stationery; attendees included Louise Rains, Bonnie Barker, Henry Friedman, Nancy Shield, Roger Goldblatt
    - Consumer movement history, 1977 (Box 1)
    - Consumer product testing, 1964 (Box 1)
    - Consumer psychology and education, 1970-1991 (Box 1)
    - Consumer rights, 1962-1991 (Box 1)
    - Consumerism articles, 1984-1990 (Box 1)
    - Correspondence, 1983-1991; 6 folders (Box 1)
    - Correspondence (Assistant Secretary of Labor), 1968-1969 (Box 1)
    - Correspondence--Clinton Administration, 1993 (Box 1)
    - Correspondence--Personal, 1988 (Box 1)
    - Correspondence--Peterson, Erik R., 1987 (Box 1)
    - Coupons, 1980-1983 (Box 1)
    - Crop genetics, 1991 (Box 1)
    - Dalkon Shield, 1987 (Box 1)
    - Egypt-Israel Peace Treaty, 1979 (Box 1)
    - Energy, 1989 (Box 1)
    - Environment--Global environment, 1989-1990 (Box 1)
    - Exponent II reunion, 1984 (Box 1)
    - Faxes, 1991; 2 folders (Box 1)
    - Food labeling, 1991 (Box 1)
    - Green Seal, 1989-1990; 3 folders (Box 1)
      Includes promotional material from Underwriter's Laboratory
    - Hazardous exports, approximately 1984 (Box 1)
    - Housing/Home buying, 1982 (Box 1)
    - JFK's Last Known Doodle and What it Means, 1966 (Box 1)
    - Long Overdue--Full Partnership for Women in American Society, 1971 (Box 1)
    - Mansions of Philosophy, undated (Box 1)
    - Meat inspection, 1982 (Box 1)
    - Notes: "The Growth and Movement Towards Corporate Accountability in the United States", 1984 (Box 1)
    - Nutrasweet, 1988 (Box 1)
    - Pharmaceutical exports--Hatch Bill, 1986 (Box 2)
    - Poverty, 1987 (Box 2)
    - Product liability, 1982 (Box 19)
    - Remarks, BYU Public Service Award, 1989 Feb. 25 (Box 2)
    - Remarks on reauthorizing the Consumer Product Safety Commission, 1989 Mar. 13 (Box 2)
    - Senate Testimony--S. 1910 (International Organizations Public Procedures Act), 1984 Apr. 12 (Box 2)
    - Snowbird, 1986-1988 (Box 2)
    - Speeches and interviews, 1977-1982 (Box 2)
    - Speeches--Australia, 1988 (Box 2)
    - Sugar, 1982 (Box 2)
    - Television, 1972-1973 (Box 2)
    - Television scripts, 1982 (Box 2)
    - Toward Standards for the Household Worker in Sweden--Report and correspondence, 1953 (Box 2)
    - Trip to Finland, 1982 (Box 2)
    - US Pharmacopoeian Convention, 1990 (Box 2)
    - Used car buying, 1982 (Box 2)
    - Warning: Reaganomics is Still Harmful to Consumers--Correspondence, 1983 (Box 2)
    - WIC, 1982 (Box 2)
    - Women, 1977-1990 (Box 2)
    - Women of Summer film, Bryn Mawr Summer School for Women Workers, 1984 (Box 2)
  - Organizations, 1973-1996 and undated; 2
    - AAUW (Amnerican Association of University Women)--Comments on topic for November panel discussions, undated (Box 2)
    - ACCI (American Council on Consumer Interests), 1989-1992 (Box 2)
    - American Committee on U.S./Soviet Relations, 1987-1992 (Box 2)
    - AT&T, 1992 (Box 2)
    - Cedar Lane Unitarian Church's Musical Journey to Eastern Europe, 1992 (Box 2)
    - Center for Science in the Public Interest (CSPI), 1988-1989 (Box 19)
    - Committee for National Security--Fifth Women's Leadership Conference, 1987 June 25-27 (Box 2)
    - Common Cause, 1990-1991 (Box 2)
    - Community Nutrition Institute, 1982 (Box 2)
    - Consumer Federation of America, 1988-1991 (Box 2)
    - Consumers Supporting Carter, 1980 (Box 2)
    - Consumers Union--50th anniversary, 1985 (Box 2)
    - Consumers Union--Correspondence, 1979-1992 (Box 2)
    - Consumers Union Archives correspondence, 1994-1996 (Box 2)
    - Food Marketing Institute, 1987-1990 (Box 2)
    - FTC (Federal Trade Commission)--Deceptive advertising, 1982 (Box 19)
    - FTC exemptions, 1982 (Box 2)
    - Howard University, 1985 (Box 2)
    - ICFTU (International Confederation of Free Trade Unions), 1993 (Box 2)
    - Join Hands, 1991 (Box 2)
    - Manufactured Housing Institute, 1990-1991 (Box 2)
    - National Consumer's League (Board of Directors), 1973 (Box 2)
    - NOW (National Organization for Women), 1987 (Box 19)
    - Pax World Foundation Advisory Board Member, 1987-1991 (Box 2)
    - Silver Spring Nursery School, 1991 (Box 2)
    - SOCAP--Society of Consumer Affairs Professionals, 1991 (Box 2)
    - Tufts Commencement, 1988 (Box 2)
    - UNA/USA DC, 1990 (Box 2)
    - Wharton/Reliance Symposium--"A New U.S. Industrial Policy?", 1981 (Box 2)
    - World Resources Institute, 1985 (Box 2)
  - People, 1976-1991 and undated; 3
    - Douglas, Paul H.--Memorial, 1976 (Box 2)
    - Eckhardt, Celia, 1984 (Box 2)
    - Kane, Edward--The Deposit Insurance Mess, 1991 (Box 2)
    - Knauer, Virginia, 1984-1985 (Box 2)
    - Knauer, Virginia--Remarks, 7th Annual Mid-American Consumer Conference, 1983 Nov. 11 (Box 2)
    - Margolius, Sidney, 1984 (Box 2)
    - Nader, Ralph, 1983-1991; 2 folders (Box 2)
    - Peterson, Esther--Biographical information, undated (Box 2)
    - Peterson, Esther--Deseret News, 1990 Sept. 3 (Box 19)
    - Smith, Hilda--92nd birthday party, 1981 (Box 2)
    - Weidenbaum, Murray, 1984 (Box 2)
- Special Assistant to the President for Consumer Affairs, 1962, 1978-1984; 2
  - Background Report on the Executive Order on Federal Policy Regarding the Export of Banned and Significantly Restricted Substances, 1981 (Box 3)
  - Businesses, 1980 (Box 3)
  - Correspondence, 1988 (Box 3)
  - Hazardous Products Executive Order, 1981 (Box 19)
  - Hazardous substances, 1981 (Box 3)
  - Kennedy consumer protection message, 1962 (Box 3)
  - Speech cards and notes, 1978-1984 (Box 4)
    Includes cards organized by topic, handwritten notes labeled "Geneva July 1984," a Steno pad with notes on miscellaneous regulatory issues of the early 1980s
  - Task Force on Consumer/Citizen Involvement--Overview of Data Gathered for Esther Peterson by, 1978 Oct. 6; 2 folders (Box 3)
- IOCU/UN (International Organization of Consumers Unions/United Nations), 1964-1993 and undated; 3
  The IOCU/UN series includes correspondence, detailed notes, and collected materials related to lobbying efforts for the UN Code of Conduct on Transnational Corporations, as well as extensive documentation of her travels as a representative of IOCU.
  - General Files, 1964-1993 and undated; 4
    - 12th IOCU World Congress--Madrid, Spain, 1987 (Box 19)
    - 1985 reports, 2 folders (Box 5)
    - 1986 Commission/ECOSOC (Box 5)
    - 1986 reports, 5 folders (Box 5)
    - 1986 reports--February (Box 5)
    - 1986 reports--January (Box 5)
    - 1987 reports, 3 folders (Box 5)
    - 1988 reports, 5 folders (Box 5)
    - Address of Esther Peterson Before the 11th Annual IOCU World Conference, Bangkok, Thailand, 12/10/1984 (Box 5)
    - Africa, 1989-1990 (Box 5)
    - Ambassador to the UN--James Pickering, 1990 (Box 5)
    - Argentina, 1984 (Box 5)
    - Argentina--ADELCO (Accion del Consumidor), 1986 (Box 5)
    - Australia and the UN Guidelines for Consumer Protection, 1984-1986 (Box 5)
    - BEUC (Bureau Europeen des Unions de Consommateurs), 1984-1989 (Box 5)
    - Bhopal, 1984-1989 (Box 5)
    - Bhopal, 1984-1989 (Box 19)
    - Bio-engineering, 1990 (Box 5)
    - Bratislava, 1992 (Box 5)
    - Brazil, 1984-1985 (Box 19)
    - Brundtland Report--Our Common Future, 1988-1989; 4 folders (Box 5)
    - Business relations paper, 1984 (Box 5)
    - Center for the Study of Commercialism, 1990 (Box 5)
    - Centre for Our Common Future, 1988-89 (Box 5)
    - Clippings, 1993 (Box 5)
    - Clippings--UN, 1986 (Box 5)
    - Clippings--UN and consumer guidelines, 1984-1985 (Box 19)
    - Codex Alimentarius--GATT--International food labeling, 1992 (Box 5)
    - CONGO Secretariat, 1990 (Box 19)
    - Consolidated list (Hazardous substances), 1984-1986; 3 folders (Box 5)
    - Consolidated list brochure, 1984 (Box 5)
    - Constitutional amendments, 1979 (Box 5)
    - Consumer Education Network--Project outline, funding proposals, 1989 (Box 5)
    - Consumer guideline reports, 1983-1985 (Box 5)
    - Consumer guidelines, 1984; 3 folders (Box 5)
    - Consumer guidelines--questions, 1989 (Box 5)
    - Consumer Interpol, 1985-1988; 4 folders (Box 6)
    - Consumer Manifesto, 1986 (Box 6)
    - Consumer Product Safety Commission, 1981-1987; 2 folders (Box 6)
      Material on hazardous substances, pharmaceutical exports
    - Consumer protection clippings, 1983-1985; 2 folders (Box 6)
      Includes some handwritten notes by Peterson.
    - Consumer protection draft guidelines, 1983-1984 (Box 6)
    - Consumer protection guidelines, 1992 (Box 6)
    - Consumer protection guidelines--Comments, 1984 (Box 6)
    - Consumer protection guidelines--Correspondence, 1983-1990 (Box 6)
    - Consumer protection guidelines--Resolutions, 1985-1988; 2 folders (Box 6)
    - Consumer protection guidelines--Speech, 1991 (Box 6)
    - Consumer protection guidelines--Statements, 1985-1986; 2 folders (Box 6)
      Includes statements and position papers for and against consumer guidelines, drafts of a statement by Peterson, UN reference material.
    - Consumer Protection Seminar: Montevideo, 1987 (Box 6)
    - Consumer protection survey, 1989-1990 (Box 6)
      Survey of state consumer protection in selected countries in the Asia/Pacific region
    - Consumer protection: Asia/Pacific Seminar, 1988-1990 (Box 6)
    - Consumer protection: Latin America/Caribbean Seminar, 1987 (Box 6)
    - Consumers and the Economic Crisis--Montevideo, Uruguay, 1986 (Box 6)
    - Consumers and Transnationals, 1987 (Box 6)
    - Consumers in Africa: IOCU application for financial assistance, 1988-1991 (Box 6)
    - Consumers Union briefing, 1986 Jan. 23 (Box 19)
    - Contacts: Business, 1984 (Box 6)
    - Contacts: International, 1985 (Box 6)
    - Contacts: Media, 1985 (Box 6)
    - Contacts: Organization, 1983-1986 (Box 6)
    - Correspondence, 1982-1993; 6 folders (Box 6)
      Includes some correspondence with named individuals; last folder also contains clippings related to insurance and general consumer issues
    - Correspondence, 1990-1991 (Box 19)
    - Correspondence--Abraham, Martin, 1988 (Box 6)
    - Correspondence--Addiss, Louise, 1980-1984 (Box 6)
    - Correspondence--Broch, Lars, 1984-1986 (Box 6)
    - Correspondence--Chronological, 1983-1984; 2 folders (Box 6)
    - Correspondence--Chronological, 1985-1987; 4 folders (Box 7)
    - Correspondence--Chronological, 1988 (Box 19)
    - Correspondence--Congressional, 1985-1988 (Box 7)
    - Correspondence--Consumer protection, 1984-1989 (Box 7)
    - Correspondence--Hawkins, Nancy, 1987 (Box 7)
    - Correspondence--Kenya, 1985 (Box 7)
    - Correspondence--Montevideo, 1985-1990 (Box 7)
    - Correspondence--New York, 1990 (Box 7)
    - Correspondence--Penang, 1990 (Box 7)
    - Correspondence--The Hague, 1991 (Box 7)
    - Dakar Conference, 1988 (Box 7)
    - Declaration: Montevideo, Uruguay, 1986 (Box 19)
    - Declaration: Tripartite--Geneva, Switzerland, 1990 (Box 7)
    - Declaration: Valdez Principles, 1989 (Box 7)
    - Developing countries, 1983-1985 (Box 7)
    - Eastern Europe trip--Austria/Vienna, 1992 (Box 7)
    - Eastern Europe trip--Correspondence, 1992 (Box 7)
    - Eastern Europe trip--Correspondence and notebooks, 1992; 2 folders (Box 19)
    - Eastern Europe trip--Czechoslovakia, Prague, Bratislava, 1992 (Box 7)
    - Eastern Europe trip--Hungary/Budapest, 1992 (Box 7)
    - Eastern Europe trip--IOCU Communications Re: Warsaw Trip, 1992 (Box 7)
    - Eastern Europe trip--Prague, 1992 (Box 7)
    - Eastern Europe trip--Salzburg, 1992 (Box 7)
    - Eastern Europe trip--Warsaw, Poland, 1992 (Box 7)
    - East-West Accord, 1981-1985 (Box 7)
    - ECOSOC--human rights resolutions, 1985 (Box 7)
    - ECOSOC--Reports, 1986 (Box 7)
    - Environment, 1989-1990 (Box 7)
    - Environment and sustainability statements and publications, 1990 (Box 7)
    - Environment clippings, 1992 (Box 7)
    - Environment--US position on environmental projects at UNCTC, 1990 (Box 7)
    - Environmental statement, 1989 (Box 7)
    - Esther Peterson: Foreign Agent, 1984-1985; 2 folders (Box 7)
    - Ethics Shouldn't Stop at the Water's Edge, Christian Science Monitor, 8/22/89, 1989 (Box 7)
    - European Data for 1992 (Box 7)
    - Expense reports, 1990-1991; 4 folders (Box 7)
    - Expenses: IOCU 1984-1985 (Box 19)
    - Export of Toxic Substances (Coordinating Committee on Toxics and Drugs), 1981-1982 (Box 7)
    - Foreign Agents Registration Act correspondence, 1984-1985 (Box 7)
    - GATT background, 1989 (Box 7)
    - GATT current, 1989-1992 (Box 7)
    - German Marshall Fund, 1984 (Box 7)
    - Guidelines--Clippings, 1984; 2 folders (Box 8)
    - Guidelines--Consumer Party, 1985 May 14 (Box 8)
    - Guidelines--Correspondence, 1984 (Box 8)
    - Guidelines--History, 1984 (Box 8)
    - Guidelines for consumer protection, 1984 (Box 8)
    - Guidelines for consumer protection--Comments, 1984; 2 folders (Box 8)
    - Guidelines for consumer protection--Press releases, 1984 (Box 8)
    - Harland, David, 1990 (Box 8)
    - Hazardous chemicals exports, 1983 (Box 8)
    - Hazardous exports, 1983-1984 (Box 19)
    - Hazardous waste dumping, 1987-1988 (Box 8)
    - Hearings, 1983-1984 (Box 8)
    - Hong Kong, 1986 (Box 8)
    - IBFAN, 1986-1988; 2 folders (Box 8)
    - India, 1988 (Box 8)
    - Interns, 1989 (Box 8)
    - International Business Council, 1986-1989; 2 folders (Box 8)
    - International conferences, 1989-1992 (Box 8)
    - International Development Conference, 1989 (Box 8)
    - Interview with Esther Peterson, 1979 (Box 8)
    - Invitations, 1989-1991 (Box 8)
    - IOCU--Annual Report correspondence, 1985-1989 (Box 8)
    - IOCU--"Doing It Ourselves", 1988 (Box 19)
    - IOCU--Food Seminar, 1990 (Box 8)
    - IOCU--History, 1980-1986 (Box 8)
    - IOCU--Information Kit on Trade, 1989 (Box 8)
    - IOCU--Latin America, 1984-1987 (Box 8)
    - IOCU--New Nations: Problems for Consumers, 1964 (Box 8)
    - IOCU--Profile, 1991 (Box 8)
    - IOCU--Regional Conference for Latin America and the Caribbean--Montevideo, Uruguay, 1986; 2 folders (Box 8)
    - IOCU--Report #1 for 1989: Feb, March, and April (Box 8)
    - IOCU--Report #1 for 1990: Jan, Feb, March, and April (Box 8)
    - IOCU--Report #2 for 1989, 2 folders (Box 8)
    - IOCU--Report #2 for 1990: May, June (Box 8)
    - IOCU--Report #3 for 1989: Oct, Nov, and Dec. (Box 8)
    - IOCU--Report #3 for 1990: July, August, September (Box 8)
    - IOCU--Reports, 1986-1989 (Box 8)
    - IOCU--Staff, 1985 (Box 8)
    - IOCU--Women as Consumers, 1989 (Box 8)
    - IWRAW (International Women's Rights Action Watch), 1991 (Box 8)
    - Job description, 1987 (Box 8)
    - Journal of Consumer Policy, 1985-1987 (Box 9)
    - Korea, 1986 (Box 9)
    - Lobby Report (Quarterly), 1989-1990 (Box 19)
    - Madrid speech, 1993 (Box 19)
    - Malaysia, 1988; 2 folders (Box 9)
    - Manitoba Institute, 1991 (Box 9)
    - Meeting logistic correspondence, 1984-1990 (Box 9)
    - Meeting summary reports, 1989-1991 (Box 9)
    - Meetings--IOCU, Bangkok, Thailand, 1990 June 20-22 (Box 19)
    - Meetings--NGO Division, World Bank, 1989 (Box 9)